GULBAKHOR MIRZALIEVA

Software Engineer | Inha University in Tashkent

+998935562750 | <u>gulbakhor_mirzalieva@mail.ru</u> | https://www.linkedin.com/in/gulbakhormirzalieva/

https://github.com/u1710099

Profile

Software Engineer with 2 + years of hands-on experience as a Backend developer working in various developmentdomains using Java, Spring framework, Trello and Git.

Tech Skills

Languages: Java Core, C++, Kotlin, HTML/CSS/Bootstrap.

Frameworks / Libs: Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Core, Reactive Spring, Webflux, Websocket, JmsBroker, Web development, Hibernate, JPA, Maven.

Web Services: Microservices, Rest, Graphql

Database: MySQL/PostgreSQL

Clouds: AWS, Docker

Testing: Junit

Productivity: Git/GitHub, Trello, MS Office, Linux, Windows OS.

Soft-Skills: Problem Solving, Research, Communication, Business, Technical expertise, Management, Critical & Analytical,

Leadership skills

Work Experience

Hayot Bank | https://hayotbank.uz/

Tashkent, UZB

Java Software Engineer

Nov.2022 - Present

Mobile App Backend: Profile Section Enhancement

- Led the backend development of the profile section for microservices for the mobile app, incorporating Reactive Spring, WebFlux, and R2DBC.
- Implemented WebSocket for real-time communication, ensuring instant updates and notifications for mobile clients.
- Integrated JMS broker communication for seamless message exchange and event-driven interactions.
- Utilized Neo4j graph database for efficient data management, handling complex relationships and data structures.

hayotbank.uz: Corporate website

- Led the development of the admin panel dashboard and corporate website, enhancing user experience and functionality.
- Implemented Reactive Spring and Webflux technologies, ensuring seamless and responsive user interactions.
- Collaborated closely with frontend developers and UX designers to create intuitive and visually appealing user interfaces.
- Conducted code reviews and provided constructive feedback to maintain code quality and adherence to best practices
- Actively participated in agile development processes, ensuring timely delivery and continuous improvement of products.

SOFT BRAINS | softbrains.uz

Tashkent, UZB

Software Engineer

May.2022 - Oct.2022

- Design and develop a Graphql, Restful APIs for different modules in the project as per the requirement
- Collaborated closely with the design and product teams to implement responsive and user-friendly website and mobile app interfaces. Dropshipping Ecommerce Project for selling Food and Beverages (https://anibeolsseo.com)
- Contributed to the development of Credivalue, a fintech project aimed at evaluating financial assets of companies (https://www.fidesvalue.com/)
- Implemented data processing algorithms and APIs to retrieve and evaluate financial data, enabling accurate assessments of companies' financial health.
- Conducted comprehensive data calculations using Python, harnessing libraries such as NumPy and Pandas for advanced analysis and profound insights

EPAM System Inc. | epam.com

Tashkent, UZB

Remote July.2021 –Jan.2022

Java Backend Developer Internship

- Worked and built a project with Database in PostgreSQL using hibernate and Creating spring boot projects
- Worked and configured Spring MVC and Hibernate in the backend to build the business logic
- Changed view forms and did crud by enhancing the efficiency of the project code structure and database access
- Designed and implemented of new business requirements both frontend and backend
- Involved in Junit Testing, debugging, and bug fixing
- Deployed Applications on AWS using Docker https://gitlab.com/gulbakhor/energy.git

Begunok Technology group

Android Developer intern

Dec.2020 -Feb.2021

- Worked and build Android application and API backed server based on Kotlin
- Designed UI/UX of the applications and Admin Panels
- Created new UI screens and key resource for layout UI work utilizing .xml, TextView, ListView, WebView, Buttons, Activities, and FrameLayout
- Participated in design discussions and pre-sprint planning exercises

Summer intern at Euro | upwork.com

Freelance technical writer

June.2020 - Present

- Support developers through answers on Stackoverflow, Twitter, Quora and other developer platforms by helping and
 resolving issues on the provided project.
- Produce a technical content, and answer technical questions from prospects and customers.
- Contribute to the documentation of the project, conduct conversation via media, video, and in-person and present the software.

Education

Inha University in Tashkent

Mirzo Ulugbek, Toshkent, UZB

BSc, Software Engineering

Sep.2017 - Sep.2021

- Dean's List standing GPA: 3.72/4.50
 - Data Structure (With C++ & Java)
 - Internet Programming
 - Application programming in Java
 - Artificial Intelligence
 - Big Data Analysis
 - Mobile Programming

Database Design

System Programming (using C)

Discrete & Engineering Math

Operating System

Internet of Things

Capstone Design

Honors & Activities

2023	Tech Summit full grant participant in Perspektywy Women 2023, Poland	Warsaw, Poland ~ IT PARK, Tashkent
2022	Tech Summit full grant participant in Perspektywy Women 2022, Poland	Warsaw, Poland
2020	Global Investment Summit – Startup Lab Pitch Finalist	GSE, Virtual
2019	ITWOMEN innovative ideas winner - 1nd place, IT Park	Tashkent, UZB
2019	GDG - DevFest Participant and Volunteered, INHA University in Tashkent	Tashkent, UZB
2018	Django Girls Workshop participant – Super Dispatch, Github, INHA University	Tashkent, UZB

Certificates

2022	Learning Spring with Spring Boot, Linkedin Learning Frank P Moley
2022	Kotlin for Java Developers, JetBrains
2020	Android Development Track successful completion, Udacity - One Million Uzbek Coders
2020	Engineering Undergraduate & Masters Asia Virtual Experience Program, Microsoft CVP, Global Talent Acquistion

Languages

- English Full Professional Proficiency
- Uzbek *Native Language*